It's my first night solo.
This is like a death march.
-What the?
-Oh my god!
Well, maybe they didn't
abandon it, maybe they died.
After ongoing tension
between her teammates...
I think the best thing for me
is just to not engage with you.
...Amber led a risky mission
to find Kel a new team.
No way!
But as she returned...
I feel like my
eyeball is going to fall
out of my head right now.
...symptoms from an
eye injury worsened
forcing her out
of the challenge...
...and leaving Joe to face
the next 30 days alone.
Made a scorpion scooper
out of a piece of copper piping.
I'm out here alone,
and I wanna be
able to go hunt, but...
I'm super depleted.
But I saw some scorpion
holes down there, and
chopping off their tails.
I need the calories,
I need something.
So, if that's...
that's all I can find, then
that's what I'm gonna do.
Getting a meal means a lot.
Any calorie score to give
my body just an assurance
that it's gonna be OK,
that we're gonna
keep feeding it.
Thankfully, the one thing in
this absolute absence of life
is scorpions.
They litter the grounds.
There are over 150 species
of scorpions in South Africa,
including the Rough
Thick Tail Scorpion,
which provides about
one gram of protein,
but has a painful sting that
can induce muscle spasms
and respiratory failure.
I'm looking for active holes.
A little technique I use
to get the scorpions,
pour water down their
hole, and then they come up,
and I see their little pinchers.
There he is.
You don't wanna dig with
your hand, that's for sure.
Sucker!
And then I dig down with
a tool, and then I get 'em,
cut the tail off,
I just want to make
sure he doesn't put me
in the hospital.
It may not look
like it, but that guy's
a substantial bite.
That's kind of the
deal with the scorpion.
They take a little
bit of technique,
and not all of them are hits.
It's not that great.
It's bending now.
This guy is plump and juicy.
No way, I was
gonna let that guy go.
In the bucket, sucker.
Got 'em! Look at that!
Look at this little hook
in the, uh... in the shovel.
Works real good separating
the scorpion from the tail.
I'm gonna go back
and cook these guys.
I got my fire going.
Got my little scorpion kebab.
Ooh-wee!
As abysmal as this place
is, as dreary as it might seem,
you know, there's hope.
Getting my survival straight.
Getting my head
straight and staying
focused on the prize.
So good.
It tastes a little
bit like chicken.
It's a little savory.
Yummy.
What I wanna do is just
have a look at
this toilet right here.
Looks like it's
made of porcelain,
so it's gonna be heavy.
I'm just trying to not think
about what was done in this
as I've got my face in it.
Now that our new
boma's almost set up,
I thought I'd just carry the
toilet down to our new boma.
-Oh, Miss Teal.
-Oh, sir.
-I got you a prezzie.
-A present?
Oh, my god, did you
really carry that down here?
-You're crazy.
-Yep.
Holy moly.
We can allocate a
bathroom inside the boma.
You don't even have to leave
the boma to go to the toilet.
Yeah, that is so awesome!
Improvising with a
bug net... There you go.
...Waz hauled in
his first protein win.
-Oh, yeah.
-Mmm.
-Oh that is good.
-I love it.
Stuff like this is what
boosts your spirits.
But the extreme heat
and stress of the challenge
proved too much for Russell...
To call this an
apocalyptic landscape
is an understatement.
...leaving Teal and
Waz to continue work
on a new shelter...
It looks like we're
making ourselves
our own little prison.
...and face the next 30
days as a team of two.
Hey, He-man, can you
come hook this for me?
There we go!
Waz and I are
making a great team.
We now have almost a
completely enclosed boma.
Our old boma wasn't
properly protected,
so we're finishing up
everything that needs to be done
to make this boma
safe and hospitable.
And we're gonna move
today, which is huge.
We got our
charcoals, some tinder,
and a couple of things
that are worthwhile, so.
And we still have the old
boma to use for cooking
and processing an animal,
so we don't have to worry
about attracting predators.
It's like a counterweight.
Oh, it makes it so much easier.
Home, sweet home.
-Ooh, yeah.
-Some tarps, some tinder,
-and a sit spot.
-This makes it official, too.
I know. We can't...
no going back now.
The absolute next thing
we need to do is get food.
I love it.
But I'm hoping a few
animals come up and feed,
and see if I can
get us some dinner.
You are the bomb.
The only thing that we have left
on our list now is to eat.
So I'm gonna walk
around and see, you know,
what other sources of
food I might be able to find.
Warthogs, which can
weigh up to 300 pounds,
don't dig their own
burrows, but take over
existing aardvark dens.
They enter these holes
backwards so that their tusks
are sticking out,
guarding the entrance
of the den from predators.
This is where the
warthogs come at nighttime.
They'll be out and about now.
There's nothing
in here, I'm sure.
At nighttime, they
come back into the hole.
We've got one, two, three.
Looks like another
one over there.
There's no prints right now.
I can't see any... I
can't see any tracks,
which is kind of strange.
But I'm gonna come back.
I'm gonna remember
where this is.
I'm gonna come back
and check for tracks,
and if this is a
active warthog hole,
then I'm gonna be
able to catch these guys.
So I don't need the
bow and arrow for this.
I could set up
some sort of spike,
throw some smoke in there,
and catch them on the way out.
I don't know, we'll
work it out, but yeah,
I'm happy I found this.
Let's go look for some more.
All right, she's still good.
Let's give these a quick check.
No?
Oh, bait's gone on that one,
so we gotta rebait that one.
Maybe we can
rebait that tonight.
With Africa and with water
holes, these catfish can stay
underground in the
mud for weeks at a time.
We know they're
packed up in there.
It's all about getting them.
Nice.
Well, found the
other water source.
After discovering a second
watering hole near the camp...
There's life in this one.
Want to rig up
these lines in here?
...Steven and Alexa
used scavenged items
to adapt their primitive
fishing techniques.
We've gotta get out
there and pray to the gods
for some food.
While Frank's
efforts with the bow...
Right there, right there.
There's a lizard
up in this tree.
Oh, he's going down the tree.
He's going around the rock.
...have yet to yield
the big win they need.
Shallow.
So I'm thinking,
go check the bird trap,
see what that's doing.
Frank's out, fingers
crossed he gets something,
because we haven't eaten
in absolute scorching weather.
It's not necessarily his
fault, but we are hungry.
So I need to be the one
that starts providing for us.
I'm at a bird trap, and
nothing got triggered.
Bummer.
Bird cage, bird trap
that I came up with,
it's just not working.
So, new plan.
I'm gonna make
it a catfish trap.
So, what I'm gonna do,
I'm gonna put a base on it.
-Oh.
-Oh, does it fit?
I love this, yes.
That old storage
cover, this thing is steel,
so it's super heavy.
So it's gonna
keep it in the mud.
It's gonna keep it
down under the water.
It's gonna be like its
own natural weight.
Plus, it gives me a base
for the cage that I needed
to begin with.
To make his fish
trap, Steven will use
scavenged rope strands to
secure the base of the cage
to a heavy storage bin cover,
which will anchor it in place,
partially submerged
in the water.
Attracted by the
bait, fish will enter
through the door and
trap themselves inside.
Steven's knowledge is
immense, and he is able
to utilize materials that
we have come across,
so we are hoping
for catfish for dinner.
So, I'm gonna find
the deepest spot.
So, I'm gonna kind of
go out here a little bit.
Let's go for a swim.
I'm an asset out
here of knowledge,
not only in survival,
but survival in Africa.
Oh, we got some holes here.
Does it need to be
completely underwater?
Mnh-mnh. I'd be
liking to have the...
-the door at least.
-Yeah, submerged.
I know how these animals
work, I know how they act,
and that makes
me feel confident.
Mechanically, technically,
this fish trap should work.
-Set it and forget it.
-Nice.
You know, the game is here.
It's just getting
close enough to it.
I need it to come together.
My partners need
it to come together.
There's a lot riding on this.
It is so frustrating.
There's food running
around, but it's always
just out of bow range.
Their senses are Uber honed in.
And right now,
they're outsmarting me.
Every turn.
So today, hydration,
fishing, let's do it.
I just want to see if
there's any new slides
with the gator in or out.
I mean, not gator,
the crocodile, sorry.
Gotcha, gotcha, gotcha.
After prioritizing their
shelter over protein...
You need to
engineer survival here.
...lack of food is hitting
Miranda the hardest.
I feel like I'm borderline
malnourished at this point.
And with another
mouth to feed...
You guys seem like
an awesome team.
I'd be blessed to
be here for sure.
All right.
...the pressure to
provide has intensified.
Catch us a fish.
Oh, that was too close.
We just need one fish
and we'll restore hope,
and then we will all
feel like Spartans.
Now that we've added a
fourth person onto our team,
we all agree that food
is the number one thing
we have to worry
about right now.
And with Miranda
not doing real well,
we're pretty...
pretty concerned.
That sun is hot.
It's like...
one of the worst days.
These are the toughest
conditions I've ever been in,
and my energy levels have
definitely been compromised.
It's just the
beginning of the day.
It's not even the hot time yet.
You should probably go
lay back down, darling.
Dehydration is the thing
that'll take any of us out
over anything else.
I gotta get horizontal quickly.
OK, I'm gonna take you back.
All right, Miranda.
Get some rest, hon.
-Roger that.
-Get some rest.
Just let me know what you need.
-Slow and steady.
-OK.
One food win would
turn it all around.
Now, Amber left her shoes.
Her feet are smaller.
I think I can repurpose
the string that she has.
I think there's a reason why
human beings have developed
these technologies, and then...
when you go without
them, you realize more why.
OK, look at that.
Mopane moth
Nice.
Yes!
This morning, I got
a bunch of scorpions.
And guess what?
Now I got us a nice
"welcome to the
neighborhood" gift.
I'm feeling like a new man.
And there's only gotta
be just determination
and stick-to-it-ness.
And I'm gonna be
sitting real pretty.
Uh, mopane moth.
I'm gonna roast it,
and I'm gonna eat it.
The mopane moth, also
known as the emperor moth,
is commonly cooked
and eaten in South Africa
and provides about three times
the protein of beef per ounce.
Gonna give me just
another boost of energy.
I know it's not a full meal, but
I appreciate these insects
just essentially falling
from the heavens like mana.
And they give me
another bit of hope,
and that's what
I need right now.
Don't know if it's good.
Never mind on that one.
I don't think I cooked
that one well enough.
Now I wanna throw up.
2 Give me a minute.
I think it was the mopane moth.
It's hard to watch
that happen, man.
I mean, it's... I'm
at a calorie deficit.
I'm dehydrated.
To lose them both, just
watch them leave your body.
And right now, every
single drop of water
and every single calorie counts.
It's hard. It's a hard thing.
I know my body's
trying to keep me safe,
but it's trying to keep me safe
in what it knows to be a world
where I can just go and
get food at the ready.
I think this was a
good wake-up call.
I gotta stay in this game.
I'm in this to win this, so...
...I just gotta be more careful.
Scared and stressed.
I am not well.
No, you can't finish
a complete thought
when you're out there.
I feel like I'm glitching.
That's exactly what that is.
I understand what your
body's going through right now.
Trouble thinking, and
processing and walking.
It just sucks.
And it's terrifying.
We have now found Hell on Earth.
Concerned about Miranda's
sudden drop in energy,
a medic arrives to
assess her condition.
I don't know. I was, like,
I was down fishing,
and then I just didn't
really rest, and it was hot.
And then my heart
just, like, started racing.
What's going on here
with one of my teammates?
This apocalyptic
environment is definitely taking
a toll on my body.
I feel like absolute
dog out here right now.
Miranda's elevated heart
rate is most likely the result
of dehydration
and a lack of iron,
as her heart pumps faster
to send nutrients and oxygen
that her organs are lacking.
Yeah.
I don't wanna go.
-You're not going nowhere.
-My body's betraying me slowly.
Yes, the only way I'm going
out is when they carry me out.
Though safe to continue,
Miranda's condition
could worsen without
nutrients, so medics will continue
to monitor her closely.
We'll get there. We'll get it.
I'm gonna go back
up to the warthog hole
and hopefully be coming
home with some dinner tonight.
Ooh, look at this.
Look at this.
It looks like a couple of
juvenile cooters have come in.
We're gonna try and sneak
up and see what we can see.
They're moving in closer.
Ooh, this is pretty exciting.
I'd much rather
hunt sitting in a blind,
but when that
opportunity pops up,
I have to try and
take advantage of it,
and I'm gonna see
how close I can get.
That's a big 200-pound
male right there.
That's a monster.
I think we're not getting
any closer than this.
These guys are smarting up.
They're not letting
me get that close.
There was one or two shots
I probably could have taken,
but I didn't want to
scare them off even more.
So it's hard to see, but...
just behind that
tree right there
is where the kudu is.
We wanna set a
blind up down there.
It's only a matter of time
before I find the perfect
opportunity and pop up
and drop one of these things.
I'm gonna be so excited.
I'm going to
the watering hole.
Wow, a lot of this
stuff is flushed out.
I don't remember
seeing this the first time,
but this is all mopani in here.
I think I'm gonna
gather some of it and...
that would make it
so that we could have
that meal with it.
My area of study and what
I'm most passionate about
is the utilization of plants.
And out here, the mopani
leaves are everywhere.
I'm trying to gather a pot
full of these new-growth
mopani leaves so that we
can boil them and get some...
something in our bellies.
The other thing is it
will enrich our water
with vitamins.
Mopani leaves, they
have a lot of tannin,
so they can be... taste
astringent kind of in the mouth.
But we'll see if we
can tolerate them.
Mopani leaves provide
about half the amount
of protein of spinach,
but are high in fatty acids
that provide energy
and help regulate
the body's immune response.
Getting a good little bit.
We haven't eaten
in four days now,
so even though this seems
like a pretty meek meal,
I am stoked that we are
going to eat something.
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow.
Oh, yeah. Your feet as well?
Oh yeah, it's hotter
than Hades out there.
-How was that?
-Eventful.
-OK.
-Yeah.
You got food?
No.
A bunch of kudu came in.
Then the two came in,
then two more behind him.
-And I'm just like, "God, that's big."
-Yeah.
Thing was huge,
the first time I seen it,
I thought it was a
baby giraffe - Yeah.
Got busted, like,
winded, you know?
Yeah.
He just smelled
something he didn't like
and was like...
Yeah, that's what they do,
they make that noise, yep.
Frank's been, uh... he's
just, he's always this close.
And I get that. It's
hunting in Africa.
That warns everything else, too.
Yeah.
It's an alert... alert noise.
But this close doesn't
put food on the table.
That one kudu would have
lasted us the whole trip.
-Oh yeah.
-Which has never come
-close enough.
-Oh no.
I can see the
weight of the world
on Frank's shoulders as
he comes home every time,
and, you know, tells us
about the near misses.
I'm gonna sit down
'cause my dogs are barking.
Either he hones in,
or give me the bow
and let me have a crack at it.
No, it's the same
as an M trap, right?
W, M, same thing.
Oh, yeah.
Normally made from
natural materials,
such as logs and rocks,
Steve's W Trap will use
scavenged roof tin and
lumber to create a corridor
that guides fish into a
closed section of baited water,
where the gap will be small
enough to prevent the croc
from entering or the
fish from getting out.
-It's worth the shot.
-Yeah.
Yeah, we're trying
virtually everything.
Yeah.
There's a little bit of
risk going into building
this trap in the water
with a crocodile.
But with the hunger
that we've got going on,
that's a risk that
we're willing to take.
I'm going back to hunting.
We've been going
for days now, fishing.
And that's not happening.
I'm increasingly
worried about Miranda.
Miranda is literally starving.
I'd really like to get a kill
and give her some food
so she has some energy.
That's, you know, a
high-pressure situation.
But I'm the hunter.
So I need to just get it done.
It's time.
Everything about hunting
in Africa is very difficult
because every single
animal here is being hunted,
so they're all always on alert.
There's nothing you can
do but just keep going after it.
35 yards,
Chalk up another miss.
Unbelievable.
Something has gotta give.
Easy.
Working on these
mopani leaves here.
The little leaves will be
boiled, and then maybe
they'll just be tasty enough.
-Hey.
-How you doing?
I need some water,
'cause I'm parched.
Look at all this mopani leaves.
Oh, thank you.
I haven't popped it open.
You wanna pop it open? Here.
First off, it's gonna
be ridiculously hot.
-Here's this.
-Ooh, they look cooked.
Here's these mopani
leaves, you boiled.
Do you mind if I dig in?
I don't mind at all.
I'm not mad at it.
I'll have a little mopani
leaf snack with it.
It's too fine.
We could totally eat it.
A little bit of a bitter tinge.
Nothing offensive.
Got some vitamins
and minerals in there
that are gonna be helpful
since we haven't been eating.
And it's gonna help our
body rejuvenate, replenish,
and all that sort of stuff.
It's real nice having a
teammate that's helping
contribute and provide.
I like the way her brain works.
-I like what she's thinking.
-Is it astringent?
Or, like, does it make
your mouth feel numb?
No.
And that's really the
only part that matters.
It's still pretty
bitter, but I think
if we cook it anymore,
it's gonna be mush.
Yeah.
Every single day, I can see
her approach and perspective
to this challenge evolve.
And I feel like I'm
gonna have someone
by my side all the way.
What you got?
Could use some salt.
Whoo!
How we feeling?
Yeah.
Miranda is having a hard
time with her energy level,
and her condition keeps going
downhill pretty... pretty fast.
So it seems pretty
obvious that we need to call
the medic for her.
It's definitely
really concerning,
-'cause she doesn't look good.
-Hi.
Hi.
I'm progressively
getting worse.
It's concerning because,
like, am I slightly dehydrated?
-I'm sure we all are out here. I know that.
-Yeah.
It's the longest I've
gone without food,
but it's, like, I'll feel
my heart start to race,
and then it's, like,
my vision goes "woof."
That's when I start
getting dizzy and go down.
OK.
You can see her face
physically going pale.
Despite hours of rest,
Miranda's heart rate
remains dangerously high.
Without treatment, she
could be at risk of shock,
loss of consciousness
and even heart failure.
Miranda,
based on the advice
of our medical staff,
we have to medically tap you
from this challenge, Miranda.
-OK.
-I'm very sorry.
OK.
You know, it's kind of
a hard pill to swallow.
I didn't expect this to be
the way to, like, medically get
taken out of the
challenge, you know?
This apocalyptic
environment, it's tried me
on every level my body has.
Thank you.
So, you know, it's a tough here.
-All right, I love you guys.
-All right, love you, too.
Miranda.
Thank you for everything.
Just keep... get
yourself better, OK?
I thought I was gonna
be walking out side by side
with my teammates,
you know? And...
unfortunately, my
body had other plans.
You know, it's probably one of
the most heartbreaking things
I've ever done.
Thank you. Catch your fish.
I will.
-Bye, guys.
-We love you.
-Love you, too.
-All right.
-Stay safe.
-Be strong.
-Drink lots of water.
-See you later.
OK.
Miranda was taken
to the nearest hospital
for treatment.
After 24 hours of
intravenous fluids and food,
her vitals stabilized, and
she returned home safely.
There's definitely a
reason why she was here.
Her body just didn't
wanna let her stay.
And it's OK, 'cause
this environment's
so hard out here.
Barren wasteland.
It takes you all the way down.
This is hell.
2 Looking for
something to
break up my pattern.
For me, I think
hunting, it's not working.
Every time the animal
came in to within probably
40 yards of the blind, they
are literally smelling me.
So it's time to use your head
and think outside the box.
Go have a look.
Nothing.
I'm just looking for anything
useful in these and...
not finding a whole lot.
Here's a smoker for a beehive.
Yeah, that's good. Could
use it for hunting, yeah.
You throw some elephant
dung in there, and just...
So we can utilize
man-made things that we find
and modern equipment
with primitive techniques.
Found a bee smoker.
It looks to be whole.
Just drop it in there.
-Nice.
-There we go.
Perfect.
It will increase my
chances of being successful.
Let me grab my gear.
So I need to get it back
out and start hunting again.
Just keep after getting food.
Whatever I gotta
do, just find a way.
-Good luck.
-Yeah.
I'll be back before
dark, hopefully.
-Hopefully.
All right.
Crossing my fingers,
I'm crossing my toes,
I'm crossing my legs,
I'm crossing everything.
Yeah.
I'm rooting for him, man.
I am gonna pop the
lid on that smoker now,
so I can add dung
to it if I need to.
So I know the
wind's going that way.
This is just gonna put the
smell of smoke in the air,
which is nothing
new to animals here.
This whole area is burnt.
So the animals are used to that.
I'm hoping it just kind
of helps mask my scent
and maybe help get this done.
I'm gonna go jump in
the water, real quick,
to cool down.
No miracles today.
I know it will succeed.
I'm feeling better.
But I don't wanna
throw up again.
So I need something in my belly.
So, I've got one more
task to do inside the kiln.
Retrieve the tool
that's going to carry me
for the next
30 days.
10 or 11 scorpions a day
gives me enough energy
to do the tasks around here.
That's not enough to
get the hell out of here.
So I need to acquire
mass amounts of meat
in order to escape
this wasteland.
Targets are so scarce.
I wanna be able to be accurate
the moment I find one.
I am getting very thirsty.
I haven't had
real water to drink.
I think I'm
dehydrating, struggling.
Boiling water takes
too much time.
In a group of three, you
can divvy out that role
and the kind of things it
takes, but I'm on my own now.
So I need a better system,
and that better system
is filtration.
This bucket's great.
This is gonna be my
water filtration system.
Because it's full of holes.
I'm gonna go get leaves,
sand, the charcoal, sand,
so I can have cool, clean water.
Not have to worry about
boiling and cooling them.
Leaves are kind of
just there to fill it in.
And then, I'm gonna
put another layer of sand
on top of that.
Essentially, it starts
out just the regular water
from the pond,
travels through the dirt,
removing any big debris.
Then it goes
through the charcoal,
removing the microbials.
Some more dirt,
just to keep that
charcoal in place.
The leaves are just there to
keep everything from falling
out the bottom, and
voila, I've got clean water
coming out the bottom.
And then I'm putting down
a real big layer of charcoal,
which I ground
down into a powder
to increase its surface area
so the water would trickle
through it and suck out all
those bacteria and things.
Charcoal, sand,
and this is really
what's gonna do the filtration.
Let's see how that works out.
It tastes like dirt 'cause
I didn't have sand.
The only important
thing is that all the water
is touching charcoal.
But what takes
with boiling water,
about two or three
hours to get lukewarm,
I'm drinking cool water
right away.
But I'll really know
it's working tonight
when I don't have stomach
cramps and I don't have diarrhea.
Mm-hmm.
I say let's do it.
Stee's plan will use
sheets of tin roofing
and scavenged
pieces of pallet wood
to create a W-shaped trap.
Fish will be lured into a
small section of the pond
where the crocodile
can't reach them.
Now it's giving me a kick up
the ass to work even harder now,
I see, like,
bubbles right there.
We see a lot of bubbles,
and I've never been, you
know, someone scared
of bubbles, but that
probably means the croc
is hanging out there.
Stupidest thing I've ever done.
Very methodically,
we start shuffling tin out
into the water, trying
to keep the croc at bay.
Even if it wanted
to try to get to us,
it'd have to hit the tin first.
OK, how about pickets
-and I'll rotate this thing out.
-Yep.
So it's super scary,
probably a bit foolish,
but we're in an apocalypse.
We're literally starving.
Desperate times,
desperate measures.
That looks fantastic.
These little tadpoles in here.
I don't know if they're
good bait or not.
I wonder if I should
just try and get some.
Variety is best.
Tadpoles are for a
different kind of bait
since we've been
trying other stuff.
And since we haven't
gotten any bites,
you've gotta keep
switching it up.
So these guys are,
like, perfect size.
They're kind of fatty.
You know, I brought in
as much weight as I could
for this challenge.
But I've lost, like,
more weight per day
than I've ever lost,
and I just need food.
I need, like, a larger
amount of food.
So hopefully we're
gonna catch something.
I'm gonna take a
break on the tadpoles.
I'm gonna get my
bug, my blade, my bait.
Yes... yes!
I got it right here, right here.
Ran that way.
Yes! Yes, yes yes!
I just hit an impala doe
right in the... right
behind the shoulder.
It looked like the arrow to
me was flopping inside of her.
She was booking, man.
So I want it to just run
as far as it thinks it needs
to and lay down and just,
just peacefully check out.
Get ready for a
tracking session.
I do see a fresh track here.
Here.
That's one of hers.
Ah, here we go.
I make my way up
towards the direction it ran.
You could see the
pugmarks clearly.
Yeah, look at this.
And right where the
trees start from the bank,
I find a bit of frothy blood.
Yeah, right through here.
And I'm thinking, this is good.
400 yards down the trail,
he's going to be piled up.
Boom.
It's happening.
2 Ah, here we go.
Look at this.
I see the arrow.
It's got some blood on it.
She come right through
here, snapped this branch off,
broke the arrow, and
the arrow landed up here.
Wow.
What are the odds of that?
I know at this point that
I've only clipped one lung.
So she was
hauling butt this way.
An impala can go a long
ways with one good lung.
We're just gonna have to
make our way through this
and try to find her.
Man, it's thick in here.
See if I can pick up
the next set of tracks.
Thorns everywhere, so
it's gonna be slow going.
Finding this
animal is everything
for my teammates and myself.
They need to eat.
Can't tell which way
she went from here.
Every predator is
probably on its way to it
right this very second.
But the further down the
tracks I get, the less and less
the blood becomes.
I gotta find this
thing before nightfall.
It's get about that time.
I'm gonna go down
and build that blind,
'cause I want to get it
all set up and ready to go
before the animals get
here so I can be sitting in it
-waiting for them, yeah?
-Word.
I'm gonna see what stuff down
here I can just move around.
So typically they're
coming in from
straight down this
way, over around
about where those
green trees are.
So they don't... I need them
not to be able to see me.
As far as the blind
goes, I don't want to use
the man-made resources.
I don't wanna change
that environment too much.
Basically, just enlarging
the structure that was
already there, so I can
move around a little bit,
and the animals can't see me.
If we get to eat, some
real nice red meat,
it's gonna be amazing.
Do a little stint here, wait
for these animals to come.
Yes, you do that.
I'm starting to get
like a little bit slower,
getting a little
bit more droopy.
Um, sure, fur side down.
Mm-hmm.
Sideways.
Yeah.
So I'm a bit worried about her.
You know, you see
the signs in people
when they're
starting to decline.
And it does concern me
a little bit because if Kel
were to go home, it
would be just two of us
having to survive
in this awful place.
It's a little scary.
She's still moving fast.
It is so frustrating
following these tracks.
It's just never
around the next bend.
Ouch.
Ow, goddamn it!
So you can see what
I'm going through.
This stuff is just all
thick, burnout, thorns.
I'm dying of thirst already.
This ground is getting hot.
The sun's high,
it's hot, it's hell.
Ow. Ow!
Time just keeps ticking by
and ticking by and ticking by.
Son of a bitch.
Yeah, I only have
so long out here.
Ow.
Out here in this
dry, dusty wasteland.
This is a very
emotional experience.
You know, as I'm
tracking this animal,
the amount of distance
this thing has covered,
you know, I'm thinking
something's wrong.
Something's not right here.
I need to find this
thing now or turn back.
There's no trail, though.
I see it.
Holy, I see her.
Oh, my god!
Yes!
Here's my... my arrow bolt.
Yes.
Ooh, she is
a little ripe, but
not bad, I can save
this. We have food.
All right, oh, my god, thank
you, thank you, thank you.
Whoo-hoo-hoo, yes!
Yeah!
So normally, I would
gut this thing here
and then pack it back to camp,
but the sun's starting to set,
it goes down
quick here in Africa,
and we got big
predators everywhere.
They probably already
smell it, so I need to get it
out of this area, so I'm
gonna make tracks for camp.
Ow!
Lot of horns.
Tracking was hard enough.
Now the real work begins.
I don't have any time to waste.
Time's ticking by.
This is not the path
I would have picked.
This ground is hot as hell.
It's the heat.
I'm just exhausting myself.
But I've always
been the provider.
It's what I do.
You know, if I can't
provide for my teammates,
I feel like that... you
know, I don't have a reason
to be out here.
I can't live with
myself if I don't.
I need a drink.
It is warming up.
Hey, y'all.
-It's dinnertime.
-What'd you say?
It's dinnertime!
Yeah, buddy!
-Oh, my god!
-We got it done.
That is what I am talking about.
Oh, my god! I knew you'd do it.
-Give me a hug.
-We got it done, man.
-I'm so proud of you.
-We got it done.
-Oh, my god.
-I'm so proud of you.
Honestly, the sight of Frank
strutting into camp
with an impala slung
across his shoulders like
the badass he absolutely is.
This is his hero moment,
and I just can't wait
to see him bask in it.
My first big kill in Africa.
So, real quick, we gotta
get the guts knocked out of it.
Frank's in. We got food.
And that, in this hellscape,
barren, burnt, scorched
earth of a land, is what
you have to do out here.
-Heart, liver, kidneys tonight.
-Yes.
Oh, man!
-Yes, yep.
-Throw something in a pot, biltong the garbage out of it.
And seeing it
happen, seeing that
bottom-of-the-barrel
Frank to the
top-of-the-mountain
Frank, just like that,
all I wanna do
is give him a hug.
-I love it. Hit it up top.
-Absolutely.
-So proud of you, man.
-Oh!
-Yeah.
-I just.
I'm seeing the look in
their faces, and I am stoked.
I'm so proud of you.
-I got it.
-Got her done.
This place is a death
scape, so we get a huge score
in a hostile
environment like this.
Let's gut her out.
I mean, we got one, two,
we got three hours of sun.
-Yeah.
-That should be, we should be good.
This is life for myself,
my teammates.
I swear to god, I could cry.
-Can I carry it? Just to feel badass?
-Absolutely.
-Yeah, pick it up, girl.
-Do it.
There's no doubt
in my mind you can.
-Come on.
-Deadlift.
There it is!
Savage!
I haven't eaten
meat since I was 13.
So needless to say,
I am very surprised
at how absolutely excited I am.
Wow.
Never in a million years,
would I ever thought
I had this moment, so thank you.
You're welcome.
It's not something I ever
thought I would relish,
seeing someone
come home with a kill.
First thing I need you to
do is take a leg in each hand
and spread them apart.
-Hold them down?
-Yep.
And yet, when you are
starving and malnourished,
it's basically dog eat
dog world out here.
This apocalyptic hellscape is
changing me in so many ways
that I just can't explain.
-All right.
-Whoa, that smell.
Oh, it's gonna get better.
All right, so, I went
ahead, got this
dope Chevy grill.
And we're gonna
turn it into a real grill.
Get a couple wheel rims.
I'm gonna burn
all this paint off.
Go over to the storage box
over there, stainless steel.
Not only do we have a
grill to get nice grill marks,
but we also have a nice
almost skillet-type deal.
Right here, I got the base of
the seat cover for the Vespa.
We're gonna use this
as our cutting board.
We're thinking outside
the box out here.
We're gonna eat the
heart, liver, kidneys.
We're gonna make a nice stew,
and the rest we're
gonna biltong, basically
making it jerky,
dehydrating the meat.
We can't let any of
this meat go to waste.
But, yeah, we're
all set up over here.
Dinnertime soon.
Yeah!
Yeah, there's definitely
something back there.
If I can just get
a little bit closer,
something magical
might happen here.
Oh.
Just had a shot at a nyala.
Shot was right on line.
Probably a couple
feet too high, though.
It's not all bad. I know
how close I can get.
Like, I just got within
20 yards of this thing.
If I can get within 10
yards of it, then, uh,
I think tomorrow we eat.
What is that sound?
That thump thump?
Oh,
A bull elephant weighs
thousands of pounds
and can outrun
me at a dead sprint.
If he decides that he
wants to take me out,
there's not a thing
I can do about it.
If it comes to him charging me,
I better make
myself right with God.
I've been wanting and
hoping for animals to return
back to this waterhole,
but for the first one to be
a young bull elephant, it's
a sign that I'm gonna have
to be more careful and cautious
so I can take this challenge
solo to completion.
I'm not alone out here anymore.
First thing we need to do,
we need to get the organs
on the grill.
As an animal lover,
as a vegetarian,
as someone who's never
really entered this realm.
You ready?
It's really hard for me
to get my head around.
I'm at war with myself.
All right, everybody
try a kidney.
-It's like a little mushroom.
-Cheers.
Cheers.
To watch Alexa start
eating meat is like a big deal.
There's no green, you know.
There's nothing out
here except for meat.
She's going against her
whole core value of beliefs.
That takes some special
kind of grit right there.
Oh, wow!
I feel like I've been
duped all these years.
-Right?
-You have.
Might be carnivore diet
for me from here on in.
Man, when you feel like
you're starving and you get
that first bite, nothing
really explains it.
It's just...
You know, there's nothing
to do but give thanks.
Tomorrow, process day.
Why does everything
we kill have to be cute?
'Cause the cute
ones taste better.
We've had yet another
unsuccessful food day.
No big scores in the
catfish or meat department.
I just wish that
it wasn't so hot
and I had something to eat
so I could actually
be more productive
'cause there's a lot
to do, but I just wish
we had something to eat.
Yeah.
It's only a matter of time
before something goes down.
I've got a couple logs
on the fire like this.
Everything sounds so close.
It's been really
freaking me out.
There goes my night.
Check out the lazy W trap.
-All right.
-Go, guys.
-We'll get this going again.
Good luck to us.
My body's just hit a wall.
I just need a lot
of meat and fish
because the heat has
been cooking me alive.
I... I... I just need food.
I need something big.
All I can do today
because of my extremely
low energy levels,
just gonna try and get
as much wood as possible
because that is something
I really love to do in general.
I like to have a
lot of firewood.
Just hoping the boys can
come up with some food
'cause I don't know how
much longer I can handle
being baked alive.
All right, let's see if we can
spot the crocodile from here.
I'm just doing absolute rows,
so make sure I don't miss,
-like, a terrapin on the bottom.
-Yeah.
When I was getting wood,
my butt was cramping up.
My muscles were cramping
up. That was, kind of, odd.
Never had that.
That's all she's got, folks.
And shortly after that, I
started having a whole bunch
of pains around
my liver and cramps
and never had
that before either.
What the hell is going on?
I must be really deficient
to not be able to function.
Yeah, I'm afraid it's
all bad news, man.
Yeah.
No fish, no
terrapins, no nothing.
I mean, we're doing
everything we can.
-Yeah.
-We really are.
Yes, it is.
It's OK.
I don't get my
hopes up until I see it.
Mentally, I've been
in the challenge
until my body just started
tripping out after getting the wood.
I just feel like my body
is just on a super deficit,
and you can't run a
car if it's out of fuel.
OK, so I made a decision.
I'm gonna go.
Oh, this is a hard
challenge, man.
I never saw it taking
me out this quick,
but I never foresaw the heat.
No. Just like Miranda couldn't.
You know, we're just subject
to these vessels we're in,
and, you know, we're
pushing them hard.
It's a horrific landscape.
I've never dealt
with heat like this.
And I don't wanna
take anything from them
because they're working
harder than I'd like,
and they still haven't been
able to replenish their fuel
and their food source,
and I don't want to take
anything else from them.
I stand by my
decision once I make it.
It is, and it is challenging.
All right, hope you feel better.
-Love you guys.
-Love you, too.
Aloha.
To be honest, I think it
was the right move for her
because she was
looking really, really bad.
It just highlights how hard it
is to survive in the harshest
apocalyptic environment
I've ever seen.
I can't believe we've
had two partners,
and both of them have tapped.
I'll tell you, I've
never seen anyone
lose so much weight so quickly.
Slow starvation,
it's a mental attitude.
Yeah.
It just all comes together.
Now, it's just me and
Stee, but in my opinion,
Stee is a legend in the making.
He is tough as nails.
He's a go getter, and we
know we need to keep going.
We've got to make
it work somehow,
so we'll make it to day 35.
There we are, me and you.
That's right, baby.
That's right.
Taking it the whole way.
Absolute end of the world.
Last night was pretty rough.
We just heard the
strangest noise.
You know, normally
we hear the kudu and...
everything grunting.
And it was, like, a...
it was like a...
kind of like a...
howling?
Growling noise?
Or a cheetah, or something?
Yeah, it sounded like that.
Just having a look around.
Ooh, look at this,
look at this tail.
Look at the lion print.
Bro, look at the size of that.
Look at this foot here.
Look at the size of that.
He's slipped a bit in the
mud, but his foot's still this big,
which is huge.
The craziest thing is,
I don't know if you put
two and two together,
but our boma is right there.
That's 40 yards away.
There's a lion print on the
ground, and it was not small.
That's not a small lion.
We need to have
our heads on a swivel.
There's dangerous
stuff out here,
and if it gets the opportunity,
it's gonna take us out,
so we need to mitigate that.
These things are walking
around right where we're living.
I'm not sure I feel super
comfortable with that.
I feel like maybe there's some
sections of the walls, that...
That's why we need to
make sure that we shore
that boma up so
nothing can get in.
I'll make sure
everything's squared away
so you feel
comfortable, all right?
OK.
There are lion prints
close to our boma,
and I don't remember any
lion prints near our old boma.
We're closer to the water
hole, which everybody goes to,
all the lions, all the other
animals, and so have we just
put ourselves in
greater harm's way?
They look bigger than they are
because of the
sliding in the mud.
Now you're just trying
to make me feel better.
Yep.
Now, we're both going
back up to the farmhouse
to see if there's any material
left to fortify our boma.
This is gonna be
a corner right here.
That's perfect.
Oh, my god.
I keep stabbing myself.
Hey, Teal, how much barbed
wire you got over there?
Yeah, I got two broken free.
I'm gonna bring those with us.
There's definitely
multiple lions in this area.
I've seen lion tracks
all around where we are.
You have to take
that into account
when you're building your
boma, you have to make sure
there's no little holes
they can sneak in.
You have to make sure
there's enough thorns
that are gonna stop them.
So, I think we're
gonna stop there.
And I'll just tie
this up to this.
The wire that we're finding
down here is all rusted.
It makes the wire brittle.
So I have to be careful.
Ah!
Do you want me to call
the medics, or you good?
Good.
While I was doing
some of this wiring,
one of the pieces came
back and kind of hit my eye.
I'm pretty sure
I don't have a
scratch, 'cause I've had
corneal scratches before,
but it does feel
a little bit bruised.
Eye injuries are the worst.
And they... they make it so
you are working with one eye
or potentially
squinting all day.
I'm going to rest my eye.
It's quite painful.
We got full bellies of
liver, heart, and kidney.
We still got a fresh shoulder,
we got two back straps.
We got multiple
meat chandeliers.
Look at this.
You cut really tiny,
thin strips of meat,
hang it on a branch,
and the lack of moisture
literally sucks all the
moisture out of the meat itself,
dehydrates it, and basically
makes it like beef jerky.
Here we have a little lunch.
I made my famous impala
and leftover meat chunk stew.
Look at that pot of stew, baby.
It falls off the bone.
We are using everything,
all the meat off this animal,
every single bit of
it, even the bones.
Thank you.
We have this pot of meat
boiling and the bone broth
and all that good stuff and
try to just get as much nutrients
out of this animal
as we possibly can.
Eyeball.
Straight for the ball, huh?
Oh, yeah.
Chewy? Slimy?
Feel like you see better?
This is where it's at.
Dessert.
-Yum.
-It's not bad.
Good.
In my previous challenges,
my partners meant
everything to me,
and it was my goal
to do whatever I
had to do to get them
to the end of that challenge.
Oh!
I've always been the provider,
so just knowing my whole team
and I get to eat together.
It's exactly like Crock-Pot
roast, you know?
God, that's a great
feeling out here.
Just seeing how joyful
they were at that moment.
It's horrible, you
guys don't want any.
It makes you feel good.
Kick back and say,
"Yeah, you know, I did that."
-Yeah.
-Mmm.
-God, that's delicious.
-Isn't it?
Take another gulp.
So good.
Yep.
I want to just light
up our firewood
so we have 10 times too much.
OK.
Well, we've got
the fire started.
My eye is super bothering me.
It's so sensitive right
now that every little thing
just makes it hurt more.
It doesn't feel good,
especially in the smoke, but...
A corneal abrasion
can induce vertigo
and severe headaches.
The introduction of rust to
the eye can leave permanent
damage to the cornea
and eventually vision loss
if left untreated.
I'm told that the eye is
the fastest healing organ
in the body, so
hopefully that's true.
Um, and so, I'm just
gonna kind of baby it,
and hopefully in a few
days, I'm just back to normal.
Teal's been great as a partner,
but I'm really
worried about Teal,
to be honest with you.
I'm hoping it's not
gonna be too bad.
I'm hoping it's
gonna fix itself,
because, to be in such
a dangerous environment
with something that's
gonna impede her vision,
that could be really bad news.
OK, I just woke up and...
...something big
is outside right now.
And it literally just
hit this car next to me.
Hey.
Something... something
big is out there.
Hey!
Get!
2 To get more accurate here,
I'm gonna need to build a range,
make sure that when I get
a chance, when an animal
does come in range,
that it's not getting away.
All right, I'm trying to
mark the distance I think it is
from my shelter to here
that would match the 25 yards
from my blind to the edge
of the water on the other side.
So, if I can get
accurate at this distance,
then that's all I really need.
All right, this guy
is a perfect target.
I mean, he looks like an animal,
was an animal, and the core
is all styrofoam, so it can take
so many arrows.
Ah! Too high.
Coming in high.
Toast.
I'm feeling pretty
good about that.
Two out of two.
Donezo!
2 Hey! Hey! Hey!
Hey! Hey!
Get!
Oh, my god.
Ooh!
I'm up for a minute
or two, just 'cause
the smoke was starting
to bother my eye again.
It hurts.
My eye is... now swollen
shut and weeping.
Yay!
Made this nifty-difty eye patch.
Last night was excruciating.
I contemplated calling
the medics several times
during the night.
The whole side of
my face was throbbing.
My pulse was through the roof.
It was not good.
Oh.
Concerned about
Teal's eye injury,
a medic arrives to
check her condition.
You want me to come out?
Oh!
You OK?
Yeah, it just hurts a lot again.
Yeah, it just hurts.
Yeah.
Yeah, it's like a
real stab, stabbing.
OK, look up.
I had a look at Teal's eye.
It was extremely red,
especially around the sclera,
the white part of the eye.
And her eyelids were
also quite inflamed, as well.
Can you see the
cut? Is it on the iris?
-Yeah, just on the iris.
-Oh.
We are increasingly concerned
that infection will step in
in the eye.
So we're gonna
clean it out first.
-You OK?
-Yeah.
-It's hard to keep it open.
To help prevent infection,
medics will flush Teal's eye
with an antibiotic solution.
But if her symptoms
worsen, they'll be forced
to pull her from the challenge.
Ah!
Oh, my gosh!
So, I'm worried about Teal.
Seems like it's getting
worse and worse.
It's troubling for me because
if she gets an eye infection,
or if it's something that's
gonna hurt her vision
long-term, I don't want that.
So hopefully we
can get her to a place
where she's comfortable staying.
I don't want her to go home.
I'm sorry, but I'm struggling.
It just, it's excruciating.
It's just too much!